Hello friends, you are watching Reporter
ji and I am your trusted host Lata
Singh.  Friends, today's news is so big that
if you have health insurance then you will
jump with joy.  Now the condition of
24-hour hospitalization for health insurance claim is
over.  Yes, now
you can get a claim even if you are admitted for just 2 hours.
Let us know how and why
this big change happened.  Friends, earlier if you
wanted a health insurance claim, it was necessary to remain
hospitalized for at least 24 hours.
But now times have changed.
Due to advancement in medical science and high-tech technology, many treatments like
cataract surgery, chemotherapy or
angiography can now be done in a few hours
and hence many big insurance
companies have changed the rules.  Now
you can claim even after being admitted in the hospital for just 2 hours.
Isn't this amazing news?
So listen now which companies are implementing this new
rule.  ICICI LBRD's
Elevate Plan, Care Insurance's Supreme
Plan and Niva BPA's health insurance
plans now cover all treatments
that require you to
stay in the hospital for just a few hours.  That means, if you
are a policy holder of these companies then this is a
big relief for you.  Now you
might be wondering why these changes have happened
?  In fact, medical technology has progressed so much in the last few years
that many
surgeries and treatments have now become
faster than ever before.  Earlier, one had to
stay in the hospital for three to four days for cataract or appendix surgery.
Now with the help of laser and robotic surgery,
this work is done in a few hours.
Due to this, insurance companies have also kept
pace with the changing times and have
removed the old 24-hour rule.
Friends, now the question arises that what is its benefit for you
?  If you have a minor
operation or treatment like dialysis
or chemotherapy and you stay in the hospital for only two to three
hours, then
in such a situation your claim will not be rejected.
Friends, this
brings great relief especially to those who undergo day care treatments.
But note that this facility
for cashless claim will be available only if you get
treatment in a hospital which is
included in the network of your insurance company.
Friends, if you want your
claim to be settled without any hassle, then
keep some important things in mind.  First of all,
check the terms and conditions of your policy carefully.
After this, make sure that your hospital
is in the network of the insurance company.
Apart from all this,
submit all the necessary documents on time to avoid claim rejection.
If your policy is old,
contact your insurance company and find out if
this new rule applies to you.
So friends, this was the
latest and relieving news from the world of health insurance.  Now
avail the claim in just 2 hours and
make your treatment easier.  If you
liked this information, then like the video.
Share with your friends and family
and don't forget to subscribe to our channel.
And yes, do tell us in the comment box below
whether you are also going to take advantage of this new rule
and if you have any questions, you can
also ask us by commenting.